# Arif Zainurrohman

# IT Business Analyst/ETL Developer/MIS Role

Address.

KP SALO No 40 B RT 02/04 Kembangan Utara, Kembangan Jakarta Barat 11610 Phone. 0822 1176 0448

Email. arif.zainurrohman@yahoo.com



**PROFILE** 

Data Enthusiasts

Experience in an Agile Environment

Successful working in a team environment, as well as independently

The ability to work under pressure and multi-task

The ability to follow instructions and deliver quality results

Programming, System Analyst, Business Analyst, Sales Analyst, Data analyst

**EDUCATIONAL** 

2013 - 2017

UNIVERSITY OF GUNADARMA

Bachelor in Computer Science.

## **EXPERIENCE**

November 2019 - Present - 6 mos

### Sales Analyst, Commercial Excellent

#### PT Home credit Indonesia (Full-time)

- The objective of this role is analytical support of Sales and others department based on IT. The holder of this position is able independently select data from database based on SQL knowledge. Design, develop, test and maintaining database, database query, etc.
- To provide analysis and data on selected data (finance, sales ,salescomm) and stress out potential issues or recommendation based on the result.
- Delivering regular (Daily, Weekly, and Monthly) and ad-hoc reports periodically as per agreed timelines.
- Provide and analysis data for Finance, Sales, Sales comm.
- Mapping Source and Target Table
- Build ETL, Create Query and Insight Table, Create job.
- Execute Initial Data
- Design data Model & Table
- Ad-hoc analysis requests fulfilment.
- Creating supporting tools for other departments.
- Support telesales for calculation bonus.
- Create supporting tools, provide, and analyst data for Commercial Insight.
- Migrate Excel Dashboard into Power BI Dashboard.
- Optimize query for Dashboard and supporting tools.
- Provide and analyst data for B2B (Business Development, Key Account, Loyalty) department.
- Manage B2B Squad to provide customized reporting and recommendation in support of ongoing business decision or initiatives.
- Provide tools for Sales Network to monitor and control POS and Salesforce.
- Assist Head of Sales Analytics in developing and reviewing the sales budget and rolling sales forecast including sales to budget variance analysis, WBR, MBR.
- Assist Head of Sales Analytics in developing and reviewing Ad-hoc request.
- Responsible for monitoring, developing & reviewing the daily sales dashboard, B2B Dashboard (Key Account, Business Development, Loyalty), Sales Network Dashboard (District Manager and Teritory Manager)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## April 2018 - October 2019 - 1 yr 6 mos

### IT Business Analyst/ETL Developer/MIS Role

#### Prudential Indonesia (PT Prudential Life Assurance) (Freelance)

- The objective of this role is analytical support of MIS and others department based on IT. The holder of this position is able independently select data from database based on SQL knowledge. Design, develop, test and maintaining database, database query, etc.
- To provide analysis and data on selected data (actuarial, finance, compliance, audit) and stress out potential issues or recommendation based on the result.
- Delivering regular (Daily and Monthly) and ad-hoc reports periodically as per agreed timelines.
- Identification and analysis of data and queries (Actuarial, Compliance, Customer Care, Finance, etc.) And provide recommendations.
- Provide and analysis data for Finance, Actuarial, Compliance.
- Mapping Source and Target Table
- Build ETL, Create Query and Insight Table, Create job.
- Execute Initial Data
- Design data Model & Table
- Ensure the SIT, UAT, TVT, BVT processes are running well
- Ensure completeness of documents for development
- Ad-hoc analysis requests fulfilment.
- Project Description : Build NBA Project / Customer Retention
  - Number of Team: 5 (1 Project Manager, 3 Business Analyst, 2 ETL Developer)
  - Role in this project : ETL Developer
- Project Description : Build MiFact SME (OMNI)
  - Number of Team : 1 (1 Business Analyst/ ETL Developer)
  - Role in this Project : Business Analyst/ ETL Developer
- Project Description : Build Twisting/ROP Enhancement
  - Number of Team : 1 (1 Business Analyst/ ETL Developer)
  - Role in this Project : Business Analyst/ ETL Developer
- Project Description : Build IFRS 17
  - Number of Team : 2 (1 Product Owner, 1 Business Analyst/ ETL Developer)
  - Role in this Project : Business Analyst/ ETL Developer

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### May 2019 - October 2019 - 6 Mos

### IT Business Analyst/ETL Developer/MIS Role

#### PT Soltius Indonesia (Freelance)

- The objective of this role is analytical support of MIS and others department based on IT. The holder of this position is able independently select data from database based on SQL knowledge. Design, develop, test and maintaining database, database query, etc.
- To provide analysis and data on selected data (actuarial, finance, compliance, audit) and stress out potential issues or recommendation based on the result.
- Delivering regular (Daily and Monthly) and ad-hoc reports periodically as per agreed timelines.
- Identification and analysis of data and queries (Actuarial, Compliance, Customer Care, Finance, etc.) And provide recommendations.
- Provide and analysis data for Finance, Actuarial, Compliance.
- Mapping Source and Target Table
- Build ETL, Create Query and Insight Table, Create job.
- Execute Initial Data
- Design data Model & Table
- Ensure the SIT, UAT, TVT, BVT processes are running well
- Ensure completeness of documents for development
- Ad-hoc analysis requests fulfilment.
- Project Description : Build NBA Project / Customer Retention
  - Number of Team: 5 (1 Project Manager, 3 Business Analyst, 2 ETL Developer)
  - Role in this project : ETL Developer
- Project Description : Build MiFact SME (OMNI)
  - Number of Team : 1 (1 Business Analyst/ ETL Developer)
  - Role in this Project : Business Analyst/ ETL Developer
- Project Description : Build Twisting/ROP Enhancement
  - Number of Team : 1 (1 Business Analyst/ ETL Developer)
  - Role in this Project : Business Analyst/ ETL Developer
- Project Description: Build IFRS 17
  - Number of Team : 2 (1 Product Owner, 1 Business Analyst/ ETL Developer)
  - Role in this Project : Business Analyst/ ETL Developer

## **EXPERIENCE**

## April 2018 - April 2019 - 1 Yr

## Application/SQL Developer

## PT Mitra Integrasi Informatika (Contract)

Project Description: Build Daily Sales Dashboard

Number of Team: 7 (1 Project Manager, 3 Business Analyst, 1 SQL Developer, 2 Business Intelligence)

Role in this Project : SQL Developer

Responsibilities/Contribution & Accomplishment:

- Create Insight Table and Summary Table
- SIT and TVT
- **Execute Initial Data**
- Create Daily and Monthly Job
- Project Description: Build Daily Sales Dashboard PAA2 (PGB/PSGB)

Number of Team: 6 (1 Project Manager, 2 Business Analyst, 2 SQL Developer, 1 Business Intelligence)

Role in this Project : SQL Developer

Responsibilities/Contribution & Accomplishment:

- Create Insight Table and Summary Table
- SIT and TVT
- **Execute Initial Data**
- Create Daily and Monthly Job
- Project Description: Build Daily Wakaf Report

Number of Team: 2 (1 Project Manager, 1 SQL Developer)

Role in this Project : SQL Developer

Responsibilities/Contribution & Accomplishment:

- Create Query and Insight Table
- SIT and TVT
- **Execute Initial Data**
- Create Daily and Monthly Job
- Create SSRS Report

Jan 2018 - Feb 2018

## **Technical Consultant Jr**

## PT Kreasi Solusi Teknologi (Full time)

- Create database object such as tables, views, stored procedure, etc.
- Create Query and Report.

**PROFICIENCY** AND SKILLS

PostgreSQL/Oracle/OBIEE

•••••• SQL Server (SSRS/SSIS/SP)

Power BI/Power Query/Power Pivot/DAX

Linux/Networking

••••••

Programming/Excel VBA/Macro

Business Analyst/Sales Analyst

**LINKS** 

in /arifzainurrohman

f /arifzainurrohman